{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Which of the following can be accessed only sequentially?", "opta": "Floppy disk", "optb": "Hard disk", "optc": "Magnetic tape", "optd": "ROM", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Magnetic tape can be accessed only sequentially."}, {"question": "MICR stands for", "opta": "Magnetic Ink Chart Receipt", "optb": "Magnetic Ink Character Recognition", "optc": "Magnetic Ink Chart Recognition", "optd": "Magnetic Ink Character Receipt", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Magnetic ink character recognition is used in banking."}, {"question": "8085 has 6 sign flags.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "It has one sign flag S."}, {"question": "JCOKE = 3JCOKE = JCOKE + 1GO TO (5, 8, 9, 11, 15, 16 18, 20) JCOKE.After the execution of above statement, the control is transferred to statement number", "opta": "8", "optb": "11", "optc": "16", "optd": "20", "ans": "B", "explanation": "It is a computed GO TO statement. Since J COKE = 3 + 1 = 4, the control is transferred to statement 11."}, {"question": "Binary number 1101.101 is equivalent to decimal number?", "opta": "13.5", "optb": "13.75", "optc": "13.625", "optd": "13.875", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Binary .101 equals 0.625 in decimal."}, {"question": "Expression ++i is equivalent to", "opta": "i = i + 2", "optb": "i = i + 1", "optc": "i = i - 1", "optd": "i = i + i + i", "ans": "B", "explanation": "i is incremented by 1."}, {"question": "To multiply a number by 8 in 8085 we have to use RAL instruction", "opta": "once", "optb": "twice", "optc": "thrice", "optd": "four times", "ans": "C", "explanation": "When RAL instruction is used once the number is doubled."}, {"question": "IC (instruction cycle), FC (fetch cycle) and EC (executive cycle) are related as", "opta": "IC = FC - EC", "optb": "IC = FC + EC", "optc": "IC = FC + 2EC", "optd": "EC = IC + EC", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Instruction cycle consists of fetch and execute cycles."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a valid variable name in C?", "opta": "1 a", "optb": "a 1 2", "optc": "a b 123", "optd": "a b c 123", "ans": "A", "explanation": "First character must be alphabet."}, {"question": "When .4546 E 5 and .5433 E 7 are to be added in normalized floating point mode", "opta": "none of the numbers is changed to any other form", "optb": ".4546 E 5 is changed .004546 E 7 and .5433 E 7 is not changed", "optc": ".5433 E 7 is changed to 54.33 E 5 and .4546 E 5 is not changed", "optd": "both the numbers are changed and their exponents are made equal to 6", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Exponents are made equal and integer part is made zero."}, {"question": "Computer virus can hide itself in a diskette but not in a hard disk.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Computer virus can hide in hard disk also."}, {"question": "The size of cache memory in most microcomputers is about", "opta": "a few bytes", "optb": "a few kilobytes", "optc": "a few megabytes", "optd": "a few gigabytes", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Size of Cache memory varies from about 16 K bytes to about 256 K bytes."}, {"question": "Which of the following computer memories is fastest?", "opta": "Cache", "optb": "Primary", "optc": "Mass storage", "optd": "Off line back up", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Cache memory has a speed of about four times the speed of main memory. It is a small high speed memory."}, {"question": "During processing the instructions, data, intermediate results and final results in a computer are held in", "opta": "CPU", "optb": "ALU", "optc": "Primary memory", "optd": "Secondary memory", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Primary memory holds these during processing of instructions."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a valid variable name in C?", "opta": "p o, t", "optb": "p o t", "optc": "po_t", "optd": "p_ot", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Comma is not allowed."}, {"question": "Z flag is reset if an ALU operation results in 0.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Z flag is set if ALU operation results in zero."}, {"question": "The power requirements of a DRAM in active and stand by modes is about", "opta": "350 mW and 5 mW respectively", "optb": "350 mW each", "optc": "5 mW each", "optd": "350 mW and 100 mW respectively", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Power requirement in stand by mode is very low 1000."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a valid real constant in C?", "opta": "1.2 e 2.0", "optb": "-2.3 e - 2", "optc": "-2.3 E 2", "optd": "-2.3 e 2", "ans": "C", "explanation": "In C real constant expressed in exponential form, mantissia and exponent should be separated by e (and not E)."}, {"question": "In a computer the instructions, data, intermediate and final results during processing are held in ALU.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "These are not held in ALU. Only computations are done by ALU."}, {"question": "The number of storage classes in C is", "opta": "2", "optb": "3", "optc": "4", "optd": "6", "ans": "C", "explanation": "C has four storage classes viz. automatic storage class, register storage class, static storage class and external storage class."}, {"question": "Most of the memory chips in static RAM", "opta": "do not require any supply", "optb": "need 2 V supply", "optc": "need 5 V supply", "optd": "need 12 V supply", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Digital chips need 5 V supply."}, {"question": "The interface chip for 8086 and 16 bit ADC is", "opta": "8259", "optb": "8255", "optc": "8253", "optd": "8251", "ans": "B", "explanation": "8255 is interface chip for 8086 and ADC."}, {"question": "Which of the following real variable names is not valid in Fortran?", "opta": "BETA", "optb": "ALPHA", "optc": "A", "optd": "AB * 2", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Operator is not allowed."}, {"question": "Temporary register in 8085 is a 16 bit register.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "It is 8 bit-register."}, {"question": "In which computer language is 'break' statement used", "opta": "Fortran 77", "optb": "Pascal", "optc": "C", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "Whenever keyword 'break' is encountered inside any C loop control passes to the first statement after the loop."}, {"question": "In a microprocessor", "opta": "all instructions need only one machine cycle", "optb": "some instructions need only one machine cycle while some other instructions need more than one machine cycle", "optc": "all instructions need only fraction of one machine cycle", "optd": "some instructions need less than one machine cycle", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Some instructrions do need more than one machine cycle."}, {"question": "Assertion (A):  If source and destination addresses are made implicit the length of instruction is reduced.Reason (R): 8085 has only 3 addressing modes.", "opta": "Both A and R are correct and R is correct explanation of A", "optb": "Both A and R are correct but R is not correct explanation of A", "optc": "A is correct R is wrong", "optd": "A is wrong R is correct", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The number of addressing modes is five."}, {"question": "Assertion (A):  Microprocessor 8085 has on-chip oscillator with inbuilt crystal.Reason (R): For frequency stability crystal oscillator is preferred.", "opta": "Both A and R are correct and R is correct explanation of A", "optb": "Both A and R are correct but R is not correct explanation of A", "optc": "A is correct R is wrong", "optd": "A is wrong R is correct", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Crystal has to be connected externally to pins 1 and 2 of 8085."}, {"question": "Consider the following program in Pascal X = 2.57X = (X + 0.06) * 10I = TRUNC (X)X = IX = X / 10.0 The final value of X would be", "opta": "2", "optb": "2.6", "optc": "2.63", "optd": "26.3", "ans": "B", "explanation": "(2.57 + 0.06) 10 = 26.3 \u2192  ."}, {"question": "Consider the following The first letter of a Java variable is lower case.Each successive word in Java variable begins with a capital letter.All other letters are lower case.A Java variable can have a digit as first character. Which of the above are correct?", "opta": "All", "optb": "1, 2, 3 only", "optc": "1, 2, 4 only", "optd": "2, 3, 4 only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "Digit as first character is not allowed."}, {"question": "Consider the following DO statement in Fortran 77 DO 52 N = 1, 10, 3 The number of DO loop executions in the above statement is", "opta": "1", "optb": "10", "optc": "3", "optd": "4", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Do statement is executed when N = 1, 4, 7, 10, i.e.,  a total of 4 times."}, {"question": "Which of the following can not be used as a variable name in C?", "opta": "else", "optb": "coal", "optc": "ram", "optd": "vendy", "ans": "A", "explanation": "else is not allowed as variable name in C."}, {"question": "In Java it is possible to have An array of integersAn array of string objectsAn array of arraysAn array on integer and strings Which of the above are correct?", "opta": "All", "optb": "1, 2 and 3 only", "optc": "1 and 2 only", "optd": "1, 3 and 4 only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "An array on integers and strings is not possible."}, {"question": "A 256 x 4 EPROM has", "opta": "8 address pins and 4 data pins", "optb": "8 address pins and 8 data pins", "optc": "4 address pins and 8 data pins", "optd": "4 address pins and 4 data pins", "ans": "A", "explanation": "28 = 256"}, {"question": "To evaluate X = (A + B + 1.2) * (A + B - C) the sequence of operation is", "opta": "+ + + - * =", "optb": "* + + + - =", "optc": "+ + - * + =", "optd": "- + + + * =", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Parenthesis has first priority."}, {"question": "In ALU 1C 74181 the addition and subtraction is in", "opta": "2's complement", "optb": "1's complement", "optc": "binary", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "2's complement is universally used in computers."}, {"question": "While selecting a memory chip the feature which should be examined is", "opta": "capacity", "optb": "ac characteristics", "optc": "dc characteristics", "optd": "all of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "All these characteristics are important."}, {"question": "EEPROM permits", "opta": "read operation only", "optb": "read and byte erase operations", "optc": "read, byte erase and byte write operations", "optd": "read, byte erase, byte write and chip erase operations", "ans": "D", "explanation": "All the four are permitted."}, {"question": "Which is not a valid Java variable", "opta": "lot", "optb": "c 1t", "optc": "s $ 2", "optd": "2 s $", "ans": "D", "explanation": "The first letter of variable name should be lower case."}, {"question": "Which of the following is invalid in Basic?", "opta": "A ** B + - C", "optb": "A ** B - C", "optc": "A * B - C", "optd": "A * B - C ** D", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Two operators cannot exist together."}, {"question": "If A = 20 and B = - 7 in PASCAL, A mod B =", "opta": "6", "optb": "2", "optc": "- 1", "optd": "3", "ans": "A", "explanation": "It gives remainder in division operation."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a computer language?", "opta": "MS WORD", "optb": "Page maker", "optc": "MS EXCEL", "optd": "LISP", "ans": "D", "explanation": "LISP is a computer language. The remaining are software packages."}, {"question": "Which of the following DO statements is invalid in FORTRAN 77?", "opta": "DO 161 = 1, 15", "optb": "DO 16 1 = 1, 10, 1", "optc": "DO 16 I = - 5, 5, 2", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "D", "explanation": "All are valid."}, {"question": "Read the following statements about files in Pascal A file is a data structure which consists of a sequence of components of the same type.The number of components in a file is variable.The components in a file can be accessed only sequentially starting from the beginning of the file. Which of the above are correct?", "opta": "All", "optb": "1 and 2 only", "optc": "2 and 3 only", "optd": "1 and 3 only", "ans": "A", "explanation": "All statements are true."}, {"question": "Consider the following C program int ramfloat alpha, gammaram = 6400alpha = 0.562gamma = alpha * ram + 1Now consider the following statements about this program ram is an integer variablealpha, gamma are real variables*, + are arithmetic operators0.562 may be an integer constant or real constant Which of the above are correct?", "opta": "All", "optb": "1, 2, 3 only", "optc": "2, 3, 4 only", "optd": "1, 2, 4 only", "ans": "B", "explanation": "0.562 is not an integer constant."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not an integer constant?", "opta": "0", "optb": "-8", "optc": "+1074", "optd": "-8.1", "ans": "D", "explanation": "Integer constant should not have decimal point."}, {"question": "Let JCOKE = 98 and LPEPSI = 42 Consider the statement IF (JCOKE - 3 * LPEPSI) 5, 6, 75 JCOKE = JCOKE + 56 JCOKE = JCOKE + 87 JCOKE = JCOKE + 11 The value of JCOKE after the execution of above statement will be", "opta": "103", "optb": "106", "optc": "109", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Since (J COKE - 3 x L PEPSI) is negative, statement 5 is executed and the result is 98 + 5 = 103."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a valid real constant in C?", "opta": "426", "optb": "321.0", "optc": "-621.231", "optd": "+201.2314", "ans": "A", "explanation": "Real constant must have a decimal point."}, {"question": "Which of the following is not a valid integer constant in C (for 16 bit)?", "opta": "321", "optb": "-162", "optc": "-65321", "optd": "+1", "ans": "C", "explanation": "The range is from - 32768 to + 32767."}, {"question": "Assume that x = 5 and y = 2. Then in Java operation x + = y, the result is", "opta": "x = 7", "optb": "x = 2", "optc": "x = 3", "optd": "x = 2", "ans": "A", "explanation": "The operator + = means add and assign."}]]}